AMBER MORRIS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

(516) 859-3337

ambermorris1997@gmail.com

github.com/amberMorris97 | linkedin.com/in/ambermoris97

SUMMARY:

Full-Stack engineer with 2+ years of experience building software applications and expertise in JavaScript, React, Node.js, and Java. Proficiency in writing automated and manual tests to ensure product quality. Familiarity with working in a CI/CD environment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front End: React, Redux, Javascript ES5/ES6, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Material-UI

Back End: Node.js, Express, Java, Spring Boot, GraphQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Hibernate, MongoDB, Mongoose, Docker, Axios, Guice

Testing: Mocha, Chai, Jest, Enzyme, JUnit, Groovy

Developer Tools: Git, NPM, Webpack, Babel, Agile Methodology, Grafana, New Relic, Netflix Conductor, JIRA, AWS, Heroku

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer - Redfin

Sep 2021 - Nov 2022

- Worked on the Home Valuation and Asset Tools (HEAT) team to build scalable, highly-reliable, cloud-based Java microservices and UI features in a CI/CD environment
- Partnered with analytics to create products that drive pricing accuracy by leveraging Machine Learning model predictions throughout offer-building processes

Neighborhood Details Section

- JavaScript, ReactJS, GraphQL, Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, PostgreSQL
- UI feature that displays various neighborhood data we have on a given property
- Accurately built out the front end based on our Product Designer's mockup using ReactJS
- Wrote Hibernate code to interact with various Redfin services and databases to surface all of the data needed into a central location
- Drew a GraphQL Schema to neatly package the data taken from our backend data stores directly into our frontends state management

Automated Offers

- Java, Netflix Conductor, PostgreSQL
- Service to automatically generate and send offers to customers wanting to sell their home to Redfin
- Implemented a Conductor workflow to orchestrate the following: the service receives data input by a customer, sends the data to various analytics endpoints to leverage ML pricing models, then packages the model responses to create and deliver an offer without any need for human intervention

Offer Score Optimization

- $\quad \quad Java, Java Script, React JS, Postgre SQL, Spring~Boot$
- Service to ensure all purchase deals have an ideal offer score of 100
- Implemented a backend algorithm that relies on pricing models and other data to generate an offer price (thus removing an agent's need for guesswork, saving on average 8 hours per week)
- Created a front-end component with React to automatically render the generated value

JavaScript Tutor - Wyzant

June 2021 - Sep 2021

- I tutored students and junior engineers in problem-solving skills, code debugging, and the following subjects: Vanilla JavaScript, React, Redux, Node.js, Express, and ES6.

OTHER PROJECTS

Jane Rosenzweig DE&I Consultant (Freelance) - http://janerosenzweig.com/

- Custom portfolio website built with React
- Features a blog API written with NodeJS and Javascript

Unshiftly (Hack Reactor) - https://github.com/Blue-Himalaya/unshiftly

- React web app with that provides a restaurant manager and employees with scheduling capabilities
- Used Redux for frontend state management and mySQL to store employee info

$\textbf{Catwalk (Hack Reactor)} \textbf{-} \underline{\text{https://github.com/Ponderous-Polar-Bear/project-catwalk}}$

- Ecommerce application built with React that allows users to browse, review, and rate clothing items
- Wrote ETL algorithm with vanilla JavaScript to parse millions of rows containing clothing data for the app

Find Your New Fav - https://github.com/amberMorris97/fynfapp

- Fullstack application that allows users to submit 3 underground artists to be promoted
- Utilized NodeJS to integrate app with Spotify API; Created a new API with Python and Flask to store submitted data

EDUCATION

Half Hollow Hills HS East

- Graduated with High School Diploma

Hack Reactor

- Advanced Software Engineering Immersive

Sep 2010 - June 2014

Mar 2021 - June 2021